<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st May 2013//EN" "http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/corehtml/query/DTD/pubmed_130501.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>

<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">24058721</PMID>
        <DateCreated>
            <Year>2013</Year>
            <Month>9</Month>
            <Day>23</Day>
        </DateCreated>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1942-0994</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>2013</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2013</Year>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Oxidative medicine and cellular longevity</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Oxid Med Cell Longev</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Oxidative Stress and Nucleic Acid Oxidation in Patients with Chronic Kidney Disease.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>301982</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText NlmCategory="UNLABELLED">Patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) have high cardiovascular mortality and morbidity and a high risk for developing malignancy. Excessive oxidative stress is thought to play a major role in elevating these risks by increasing oxidative nucleic acid damage. Oxidative stress results from an imbalance between reactive oxygen/nitrogen species (RONS) production and antioxidant defense mechanisms and can cause vascular and tissue injuries as well as nucleic acid damage in CKD patients. The increased production of RONS, impaired nonenzymatic or enzymatic antioxidant defense mechanisms, and other risk factors including gene polymorphisms, uremic toxins (indoxyl sulfate), deficiency of arylesterase/paraoxonase, hyperhomocysteinemia, dialysis-associated membrane bioincompatibility, and endotoxin in patients with CKD can inhibit normal cell function by damaging cell lipids, arachidonic acid derivatives, carbohydrates, proteins, amino acids, and nucleic acids. Several clinical biomarkers and techniques have been used to detect the antioxidant status and oxidative stress/oxidative nucleic acid damage associated with long-term complications such as inflammation, atherosclerosis, amyloidosis, and malignancy in CKD patients. Antioxidant therapies have been studied to reduce the oxidative stress and nucleic acid oxidation in patients with CKD, including alpha-tocopherol, N-acetylcysteine, ascorbic acid, glutathione, folic acid, bardoxolone methyl, angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor, and providing better dialysis strategies. This paper provides an overview of radical production, antioxidant defence, pathogenesis and biomarkers of oxidative stress in patients with CKD, and possible antioxidant therapies.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, No. 325, Section 2, Cheng-Kung Road, Neihu, Taipei 114, Taiwan ; Graduate Institute of Medical Science, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei 114, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            <AuthorList>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Sung</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Chih-Chien</ForeName>
                    <Initials>CC</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Hsu</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yu-Chuan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YC</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Chen</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Chun-Chi</ForeName>
                    <Initials>CC</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Lin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yuh-Feng</ForeName>
                    <Initials>YF</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author>
                    <LastName>Wu</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Chia-Chao</ForeName>
                    <Initials>CC</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>ENG</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType>REVIEW</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>8</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <MedlineTA>Oxid Med Cell Longev</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101479826</NlmUniqueID>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>5</Month>
                <Day>7</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>16</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="epublish">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>8</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/301982</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24058721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3766569</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>
